quirm.net 2018-10-28

# Privacy – quirm.net

## Privacy

### What personal data we collect and why we collect it

#### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site, we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it ([Gravatar’s privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/)). After approval of your comment, your chosen profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

#### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

#### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content — including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### Analytics

Most sites generate log files that record visitors’ use of the site. We may analyse log file information in order to make changes to the site, based on the way that visitors move around it. Log files do not contain any personal information and they cannot be used to identify any individual patterns of use.

### Who we share your data with

If you submit a comment to this site, we share your data with the Gravatar service and, possibly, an automated spam detection service.

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security w.

Please use our [contact form](http://quirm.net/contact/) for any privacy policy enquiry.

### Your contact details

We value the privacy of our visitors and understand that they do not want their names or email address details to be passed onto third parties. We will not communicate personal information of this type, in any form, to any third party without the express permission of the individual(s) concerned.

### Additional information

This site does not receive data from any third party other than from the Gravatar service as outlined above. We do not carry out any profiling with user data.

### Application of this policy

This policy applies solely to this web site. Where we offer links to — or embedded content from — other sites, it should be understood that we do not endorse, nor can we be held responsible for, the privacy policies of those sites.
